Abdullah Qureshi

+91 9757208990 • abdullahqureshi00@gmail.com • www.linkedin.com/in/abdullahqureshi99/

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Mobile Developer | Web Developer | Junior Software Developer

I have 1 year of programming experience in building mobile applications using Xamarin Forms. I am also familiar with SQL and React Native. I am competent in performing roles that include programming, testing, documentation, and deployment of Software applications. Bringing forth expertise in design, installation, testing and maintenance of applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Godrej InfoTech Ltd- *Mumbai*

07/2021 - 05/2022

Senior Executive

As a mobile developer, I was part of a team that developed and maintained scalable applications I performed various duties including but not limited to the following:

- Carried out mobile development and implementation that assisted in developing internal mobile applications for the organization.
- Tested mobile applications, identified bugs, debugged, and resolved issues as reported by testing team.
- Documented applications developed according to system development standards and ensured that the accepted methodology was followed.
- Maintained source code of the developed system and followed best practices to collaborate with teammates.

OTTOEDGE Services - Mumbai

09/2022 - Present

Web Developer

As a junior web developer, my work included developing frontend design and well as managing backend of the website.

- Designed and developed user friendly and responsive website including user Login page.
- Finding inconsistencies and solving in the application.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML/CSS	Java
C# (Xamarin)	Node.js
SQL Server	React Native
React	Javascript

Abdullah Qureshi +91 9757208990

EDUCATION

Xavier Institute of Engineering - *Mumbai*

Bachelor of Engineering - Information Technology, 2018 -2021

Grade: 7.99

Babasaheb Gawde Institute of Technology - Mumbai

Diploma - Computer Technology, 2015 -2018

Grade: 80%

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Mastery of Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint) and Google Suite (Docs, Sheets, Slides).

- Familiar using Different Operating Systems.
- Excellent communication skills with a focus on team-building and client relations.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

MERN Ecommerce Application

- Responsive Frontend UI using React JS
- Built Backend using Node.js and Express to handle server requests.
- Usage of MongoDB for Data Storage and Supports CRUD operations.

House Price Prediction

- Developed Frontend using HTML and CSS.
- Used Python and Machine Learning for processing Data.
- Evaluates various parameters and estimates price of Property based on the input Dataset.

Question Paper Generator System

- Developed using ASP .Net and C# and SQL Server was used as Database.
- Provides a comprehensive solution to conduct exams with varying level of difficulty.

LANGUAGE COMPETENCIES

• English: Full Professional Proficiency

• Arabic: Professional Working Proficiency

• Hindi: Native Language